aoi hoshi ni senritsu ga hashiru
a
o
i
ho
shi
ni
se
n
ri
tsu
ga
ha
shi
ru
A shudder runs over the blue planet
푸른 지구에 전율이 흐른다
kuroi arashi chikazuku toki
ku
ro
i
a
ra
shi
chi
ka
zu
ku
to
ki
It's the time the dark storm approaches
검은 폭풍이 닥쳐오는 순간
kokoro no oku de mezameru HERO
ko
ro
no
o
ku
de
me
za
ru
HE
RO
It's as if a hero is awakening on the inside
마음 속의 눈을 뜬 영웅들이여
tobitatsu no da furimukazu ni
to
bi
ta
tsu
no
da
fu
ri
mu
ka
zu
ni
Fly away and don't look back!
뒤돌아보지 말고 날아가라
DAGWON kagayake DAGWON
DA
G
WON
ka
ga
ya
ke
DA
G
WON
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Brave Command Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Dagwon... Shine on!! Dagwon!
다그온 빛나라!! 다그온
heiwa mamoru namae sa
he
i
wa
ma
mo
ru
na
ma
e
sa
The name that protects the peace
평화를 지키는 이름이다
DAGWON oretachi DAGWON
DA
G
WON
o
re
ta
chi
DA
G
WON
Dagwon! We are Dagwon!
다그온 우리는 다그온
yume wa zettai watasanai
yu
me
wa
ze
t
ta
i
wa
ta
sa
na
i
We will never hand over our dream
꿈은 절대로 넘겨줄 수 없다
afureru yuuki te ni shitai nara
a
fu
re
ru
yu
u
ki
te
ni
shi
ta
i
na
ra
To grab the overflowing courage
넘쳐흐르는 용기를 거머쥐고 싶다면
tsuyoku tsuyoku yuujou shinjiru koto sa
tsu
yo
ku
tsu
yo
ku
yu
u
jo
shi
n
ji
ru
ko
to
sa
We believe in our friendship firmly
우리 우정을 굳게 믿는 거다
kizutsuku koto mo osore wa shinai
ki
zu
tsu
ku
ko
to
mo
o
so
re
wa
shi
na
i
We are not afraid of getting hurt
상처입는 것도 두렵지 않아
mugendai no mirai wo egaku sono tame ni
mu
ge
n
da
i
no
mi
ra
i
wo
e
ga
ku
so
no
ta
me
ni
In order to reach that infinite future!
무한대의 미래를 그려내기 위해서라면
Brutal aliens escaped from Space Prison Sargasso.
우주 감옥 사르갓소의 흉악한 우주인들
To protect the Earth from those evil hands, the brave high school students, Dagwon, keep fighting on to this day.
그 마수로부터 지구를 지키기 위해 오늘도 계속해서 싸우는 고등학생 용자 다그온
The result of their further power up is Dag Fire's Strength Fusion, Power Dagwon.
그들의 거듭되는 파워업이 바로 다그 파이어의 강력 합체 파워 다그온인 것이다
En and Geki, the Reputed Detectives
소문의 형사 엔 & 게키
Vicious Space Policeman Deathcop
Appears
흉악 우주 경관 데스캅
등장
Emergency order. Emergency order.
긴급 지령, 긴급 지령
Deathcop has appeared on the south street of Sankai's Kakui in Kera.
케라 내의 카쿠이의 산카이 남쪽 거리에 데스캅이 나타났습니다
Emergency backup requested.
시급히 지원 부탁드립니다
시급히 지원 부탁드립니다!
-Deathcop?
-Yeah.
-데스캅?
-그래
That guy's the suspect of police assault incidents happening in the streets.
거리에서 잇달아 발생하는 경찰 습격 사건의 범인이야
We don't know why, but he's only targeting the police.
목적은 모르겠지만, 경찰만 노리고 있어
It's like a police hunt.
마치 경찰 사냥 같군
Moreover, it's so suddenly appearing and disappearing, that even the police are having a trouble.
게다가 신출귀몰해서 경찰도 애먹고 있는 상황인 것 같아
I'll tell you as of today!
오늘은 반드시 말씀드리겠습니다
Ms. Maria, um...
마리아 씨, 저기…
With me... with me...
저와… 저와… !
Um...
저기…
Maria went out to find Tsuchinoko.
마리아 씨라면 츠치노코 찾으러 나가서 지금 없어요
No, no, no!
안돼, 안돼, 안돼!
If you have a present for Maria, I'll give it for ya, Geki.
마리아 줄 선물이면 내가 맡아줄까, 게키?
D- d- don't make fool of me, En!
바, 바보같은 소리마, 엔!
I'm not doing such an irresolute thing!
내가 그런 나약한 짓을 할리가 없잖아!
Then what are you hiding?
그럼 뭘 숨기고 있다냐?
N- nothing you'd care about!
아, 아무것도 아니야!
Don't look.
이, 이봐, 보지 말라구;;
Wow, you managed to get rose splinters in your neck.
입 속에 장미 가시가 박혔구만~
However, if we don't do something about Deathcop, public security will be thrown into confusion.
하지만 이대로 데스캅을 내버려두면 마을의 치안은 혼란스럽게 되고 말아
Also, if Deathcop is an alien from Sargasso, the police cannot do anything about it.
게다가 데스캅이 사르갓소의 우주인이라면 경찰로선 도저히 감당할 수 없어
If that's the case, what are we doing just standing around?
그런 거라면, 뭘 멍하니 있는 거야?
Let's just go catch him by ourselves!
우리가 붙잡으면 되는 거잖아
That's what we're trying to figure out!
그러니까 어떻게 잡을지 그 방법을 지금 생각중이잖냐
Have an idea, Geki?
뭐 아이디어라도 있냐, 게키?
Guts! With guts, nothing is impossible!
근성이야! 근성만 있으면 불가능 따윈 없다!
Just as always, talking to you doesn't work at all.
하아~ 너하곤 말이 안 통한다
We'll just have to split up and find out.
각자 흩어져서 조사할 수 밖에 없겠군요
Right. Seems so.
그런 것 같군
That's it! I have an idea!
맞다!
나 좋은 생각이 떠올랐어
Even for me, it looks pretty nice!
내가 입은 거지만, 잘 어울리는구만
It doesn't look like the costumes borrowed from the theatrical club!
연극부에서 빌린 의상으로는 안 보이는데~
We will act as bait for bringing out Deathcop by disguising ourselves as police officers.
경찰로 변장한 우리가 미끼가 돼서 데스캅을 끌어낸다
In other words, it's a sting operation.
다시말해, 미끼 수사란 거지
Let's do this, Drill Detective!
잘 해보자구, 드릴 형사!
Yeah! Leave it to me, Fire Detective!
오우! 맡겨만 두라구, 파이어 형사!
Alright! Let's do this!
좋아!
What'cha doin'?
뭐하는 거냐?
Don't you know?
모르냐?
The FBI does this.
FBI는 이렇게 한다구
If Ms. Maria sees this, she'll fall in love with me!
마리아 씨가 보면, 틀림없이 나한테 반하겠지
She'll go full Mr. Geki, you look fabulous!
"게키 씨, 멋져요"라고 말이야~
What's so great about that occult girl?
그런 오컬트 소녀가 뭐 좋다고…
Your taste is so bad.
취미 한 번 고약하다
What was that?!
뭐라고?!
I will not forgive anyone insulting Ms. Maria!
마리아 씨를 모욕하다니, 용서 못해!
I'll catch you red-handed!
현행범으로 체포한다!
Hey, what was that for?
이봐, 뭔 짓이야?
Help me, police officers!
이봐요, 경찰 아저씨!
My Kumi is lost!
우리 쿠미가 행방불명이예요!
Th- that is, uh, there are possibilities of kidnapping, too!
뭐, 그, 그건 유괴의 가능성도 있습니다!
Prepare for reverse investigation, Fire Detective!
역탐지 준비다, 파이어 형사
Reverse investigation?
역탐지?
You idiot!
바보 녀석!
We're preparing just in case the criminal is demanding a ransom!
범인이 몸값 요구 전화를 할 경우에 대비하는 거야
-So, how old is Kumi?
-5 years old.
-그래서, 쿠미의 나이는?
-5살이예요
-Oh, it's an age of cuteness!
-Of course!
-오오, 한창 귀여울 때군요
-그야 물론~
And what's distinctive about her?
그리고, 특징은?
There are long whiskers on her face.
얼굴은 수염이 긴 게 특징이고…
I see, your daughter grows beards.
따님은 수염을 기르고 있군요
Her body is gray, and arms and legs are dark brown.
몸은 회색이고 팔다리는 암갈색이예요
She definitely is a peculiar daughter.
참 특이한 따님이시군요
Of course! She is a pretty Persian cat who even got first place in the competition!
어머, 콩쿠르에서 1등상도 받은 정말 예쁜 페르시안 고양이예요
Wa- was it a cat?!
고, 고양이라구요?
It's not a time for stupid shenanigans!
낡아빠진 콩트 하고 있을 때가 아니야!
We're sorry, but we are on a more important matter.
미안하지만 우리는 지금 중요한 사건을 맡고 있어서요
Wait! Don't you see how I am troubled? Aren't you willing to help me?
이봐요! 내가 이렇게 곤란해하는데 못 도와주겠단 말이예요?!
Do you guys call yourselves policemen?!
당신들 그러고도 경찰이야?!
Even if you say so, we are...
아무리 그런 소리 해도 우리는…
The duty of policemen is to help honest people!
선량한 시민을 구하는 것이 경찰의 임무
We understand! Let's go, Fire Detective!
잘 알겠습니다!
가자, 파이어 형사
Hey! I guess I won't be escaping...
여봐!
별 수 없구만…
Hey, you!
느아악, 이놈아!
There!
저기 있다!
-Hey!
-Stop!
-아앗!
-거기 서라!
Kumi, let's go back.
쿠미, 돌아가자~♡
She could at least show some appreciation!
나 참, 고맙단 말 정도는 하고 가지
This is part of work! Don't grumble!
이것도 일이야
꿍시렁대지 말라구
You say finding a cat is a work?!
고양이 찾는 게 일이냐!
Don't forget we are Dagwon!
말 해 두겠는데, 우리는 다그온이라구!
Dagwon!
다 · 그 · 온 · !
8th car here. Deathcop appeared on 3rd street in Sankai!
여기는 8호차
산카이 3가에 데스캅 출현!
We need backup right now!
지금 즉시 지원 부탁한다!
Let's go, Geki!
가자, 게키!
Hey, what's holding ya?
이봐, 왜그래?
Don't you know, Fire Detective?
알겠냐, 파이어 형사
Running suits are more for a detective than staying in a patrol car! Drill Detective, setting off!
형사란 말이지 경찰차에 틀어박혀 있는 것 보다 달리는 모습이 훨씬 잘 어울린다구 드릴 형사, 출동이다!
Yeah, right.
니 맘대로 해라
I want to show this valiant look to Ms. Maria!
이 씩씩한 모습을 마리아 씨에게 보여드리고 싶구만
See you at the scene, Drill Detective!
먼저 실례, 드릴 형사님~
W- wait!
기, 기다려~
Can a protector of peace be this weak?
정의를 지키는 경찰이 이리 약해빠져서 되겠는가?
Those useless brats...
도움도 되지 않는 녀석들…
Go to hell right now!
어서 죽어버려라!
That's as far as you go, Deathcop!
거기까지다, 데스캅!
Leave this brat to me! We're arresting you!
이녀석은 내게 맡겨라!
현행범으로 체포한다!
You idiot, resist and I'll shoot!
바보 녀석, 반항하면 쏜다!
You are the idiot!
바보는 너라구!
Don't you know that gun is a prop of the theatrical club?
그 권총은 연극부 소도구잖아!
Oh, I forgot.
이런, 까먹고 있었다;;
Try Dagwon!
트라이 다그온
Fire En!
파이어 엔
Shoulder Burn!
숄더 번!
Damn Dagwon...
다그온 녀석…
Wh- what?
아, 아니?!
I'll do it too!
나도 변신이다!
Try Dagwon!
트라이 다그온
Drill Geki!
드릴 게키
Rock Crusher!
락 크래셔!
I was waiting for you! You dogs of the Space Police Organization!
기다리고 있었다 우주 경찰 기구의 개 녀석들!
What?!
뭐야?!
What a strong bastard!
엄청난 녀석이다!
Don't say weak, Fire Detective!
약한 소리 하지마
파이어 형사!
Geki! Damn...
게키!
젠장…!
-Geki, hide!
-Sorry...
-게키, 숨어 있어
-미안해
Is that all you can do?
겨우 그정도냐…
Is that all?
겨우 그정도냐!
Aren't you Dagwon, the protector of peace?
너는 정의를 지키는 다그온이 아니더냐?
What power! What the hell are you?
엄청난 힘이다!
대체 네녀석은…?
As a previous member of Space Police Organization, I've gone through numerous battles against vile aliens.
나는 과거에 우주 경찰 기구의 한사람으로서 흉악한 우주인들을 상대로 무수한 싸움을 경험해왔다
And they feared me, so they called me Space Policeman Deathcop.
그리고 녀석들은 나를 두려워해서 우주 경관 데스캅이라고 불렀다
Space Policeman?!
우주 경관?!
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Original Korean Subtitles by Jaebari (재바리)
Translated to English by Subdivers
Checked by Great Exkaiser103
자막 원본(번역): 재바리
수정: Subdivers
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
I made many casualties by including innocent people to capture the villains.
나는 범인 체포를 위해 일반인까지 휘말리게 하여 수많은 희생자를 냈다
To achieve the objective, some casualties are expected.
목적을 달성하기 위해서 다소의 희생은 당연한 것
But still, those brats from Space Police Organization judged me in the name of justice!
그런데도 우주 경찰 기구 녀석들은 정의의 이름으로 나를 심판했다!
What is justice?
뭐가 정의란 말이냐…
This is my turn to judge!
이번엔 내가 심판할 차례다
I'll kill all of you Dagwon, for siding with Space Police Organization!
우주 경찰 기구에 가담한 너희들 다그온을 싸그리 죽여주마!
Die!
죽어라!
Why you-! You're just a villain who disgraces the name of justice!
이자식! 정의의 이름을 더럽히는 악당 녀석!
I will not forgive!
내가 용서치 않겠다
Don't do what you can't!
터무니없는 짓 하지마!
Hmph. You idiot.
흥, 바보같은 녀석…
Drill Knuckle!
드릴 너클!
Geki, are you okay?
게키, 괜찮아?
It wouldn't have been interesting without that!
이정도는 해 주지 않으면 재미없지!
You punk, still...
이, 이자식, 아직…
I'll show you my true power.
나의 진정한 힘을 보여주마
Space Police Deathcop! Merging Fusion!
우주 경관 데스캅 융합합체
(融合合體)
What?!
뭐야?!
Deathcop Powered!
데스캅 파워드
Fire Stratus!
파이어 스투라투스!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체
(融合合體)
Dag Fire!
다그 파이어
Strength Fusion!
강력합체
(剛力合體)
No, you don't!
그렇게는 안되지!
We are too outmatched!
화력 차이가 너무 커!
Let's go!
간다!
How's this?!
어떠냐!
What?!
아니?!
Stop this futile resistance!
쓸데없는 저항은 관둬라!
Now!
지금이다!
Strength Fusion!
강력합체
(剛力合體)
Power Dagwon!
파워 다그온
Let's go, Deathcop!
간다, 데스캅!
Shovel Upper!
셔벨 어퍼!
Drill Drop!
드릴 떨구기! 까짓거!
Shovel Shield!
셔벨 실드!
Let's go!
간다!
Finishing move! Fire Claw!
필살! 파이어 클로!
I got him!
잡았다!
I'll choke you to death!
조여 죽여주마!
The way of the spirit, the Kagemurasaki!
명도 카게 무라사키(名刀影紫)!
Shadow Dagwon!
섀도우 다그온!
Armor Buster!
아머 버스터!
Liner Dagwon!
라이너 다그온!
You all came, Dagwon fools!
모두 모였구나, 다그온 놈들!
Liner Blizzard!
라이너 블리자드!
Shadow Beast King Slash!
섀도우 아왕참(牙王斬り)!
Are you alright?
괜찮아?
Yes, somehow.
아아, 그럭저럭
Wh- what power!
어, 엄청난 힘이다!
I'll take you three down at once.
3대 한꺼번에 끝장내 주마
Death Buster!
데스버스터!
Are you two okay?!
괜찮아, 둘 다?!
Maybe... probably...
아아… 그럭저럭…
But... we can't stand up...
하지만… 이젠 서지도 못하겠어…
Something... Something!
뭔가, 뭔가!
There has to be a way to take him down...
녀석을 쓰러뜨릴 방법이…
The Fire Shovel is a bit more of an improvement.
파이어 셔벨에는 약간의 개량이 더해졌어요
-Improvement?
-You'll see when you use the Infinity Cannon next time.
개량이라뇨? 다음번에 무한포를 사용할 때 알게 될 거예요
It's the Infinity Cannon!
무한포군!
Alright, Gunkid!
좋았어, 건키드!
Gunkid, Change!
건키드 체인지!
Target Lock!
타깃 록(TARGET LOCK)!
Set on!
세트 온(SET ON)!
Interesting! I'll pierce through your heart.
재미있군! 이번엔 심장을 꿰뚫어 주마
Power Dagwon...
파워 다그온…
-It's a duel, Dagwon!
-Sure!
-승부다, 다그온!
-오우!
Fire!
발사(FIRE)!
Am I going to be defeated by justice again?
나는 또다시 정의에게 지는 것인가?!
Damn you, Dagwon... like this...
이놈, 다그온… 이대로…
The notorious Deathcop ends like this.
악명 높은 데스캅도 이꼴이냐?
You are... Hido!
네, 네놈은 히드…!
I have no business with such a useless guy.
쓸모없는 놈에게 볼일은 없어
Farewell.
잘 가라
You're tough, I see! I thought you were dead.
하지만 너도 터프하구만
확실히 죽은 줄 알았어
Remember this, you brat!
기억해 둬라, 요놈아
When I die, I'll return as a ghost to haunt you!
내가 죽으면 반드시 귀신이 돼서 나와줄 테니까 말이야
Then Maria will be happy too!
그럼 마리아도 틀림없이 기뻐할 거다
Ms. Maria will?!
마리아 씨가?!
You are useless alive, but
살아있는 너는 아무런 쓸모도 없지만
you as a ghost is an excellent study sample!
유령이 된 너라면 훌륭한 연구 재료지
Be careful of what you say!
말하면 다냐?!
Wanna fight after a long time?
뭐야, 오랜만에 붙어 볼까?
Pervert! Help me!
치한이야! 훔쳐봤어!
A case!
사건이다!
-Let's go, Drill Detective!
-Right, Fire Detective!
-가자, 드릴 형사!
-오우, 파이어 형사!
The sun suddenly called me
태양이 갑작스레 나를 불러내서
taiyou ga fui ni ore wo izanau
To come to the blue sea
푸르게 비치는 바다로 만나러 갔지
aoku sukitooru umi ni ai ni kita
The ripples are coming and going
밀려왔다 돌아가는 잔물결
yosete wa kaesu sazanami
An endless melody
멈추지 않는 멜로디
tomaru koto nai MELODY
To keep that shape for eternity
그 모습을 영원히 유지할 수 있도록
sono sugata towa ni tsunagu you ni
I'll follow the fate of the dream
꿈의 행방을 뒤쫓아 갈 거야
oikakete yuku yo yume no yukue
Sparkling far away
멀리서 반짝이던
tooku kirameita
A Prism in the Wind
바람 속의 프리즘
kaze no naka no PRISM
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Preview for Next Episode
용자지령
다그온
차회예고
The school festival is now here!
찾아왔습니다, 학원제!
You look you have a lot to do!
오오, 의욕 만땅인데~
Our Supernatural Phenomenon Research Club will do a haunted house!
우리 초상 현상 연구회는 물론! 도깨비집을 합니다~
Vice principal Ijuuin is doing his best for the yakisoba (fried noodles) booth!
이쥬인 교감은 볶음국수집에 목숨 걸었다던데
-But a typhoon has appeared!
-Something's not right about this typhoon.
-하지만 태풍이 와버렸어
-이 태풍, 아무래도 이상해
-Is it an alien?
-Then Dagwon will take care of them!
-우주인인가?!
-그럼 다그온에게 해치워 달라고 해야지
Next time on Yuusha Shirei Dagwon! A School Festival Calls for a Storm
다음회 용자지령 다그온
폭풍을 부르는 학원제
Vice principal! We're looking for your Try Yakisoba!
교감 선생님, 트라이 볶음국수, 기대하고 있다구요!
A School Festival Calls for a Storm
폭풍을 부르는 학원제